# SHANMUKH GORLE

Charlotte, NC 28262 | +1 929-944-5431 | gorleshanmukh@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/gorleshanmukh | www.shanmukhgorle.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Proficient Java developer with more than four years of professional experience developing enterprise-level web applications. A year's experience in leading a team and performing the duties of a scrum master. A key contributor to all phases of the software development lifecycle, with a talent for collaboration with diverse cross-functional teams. Implemented several projects through agile methodologies using advanced frameworks, web services, and design patterns.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

ProgrammingJAVA, C, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSSWeb and FrameworksReactJS, Angular 2+, Spring, Spring BootDatabasesMS SQL Server, SQLite, MySQL, MongoDB

Tools VS Code, IntelliJ, SQL Server Management Studio

Cloud Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure

Version Controls GitHub, Bitbucket

#### **EDUCATION**

University of North Carolina, Charlotte, NC, USA

August 2022 – December 2023

Master of Science in Computer Science

4.0/4.0 GPA

Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology, Odisha, India

May 2015 – April 2019

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science

7.37/10 GPA

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### North Carolina Research Center, Kannapolis, NC

Research Assistant/Software Developer

August 2022 - Present

- Working on spring to spring boot migration
- Wrote Scripts for CI/CD

# Athenahealth, Chennai, India

Member of Technical Staff (SDE-I)

November 2021 – June 2022

- Worked on an application that handles payments between hospitals and insurance companies in the United States
- Automated disaster recovery process for applications hosted in Amazon Web Services through Jenkins and CloudFormation
- Performed the role of a scrum master and led a team of two junior developers
- Worked on discoveries for filling backlogs/work items for the upcoming release

## Cognizant, Chennai, India

**Programmer Analyst** 

May 2019 - November 2021

- Built an application that helped pilots manage their flights and trips
- Wrote scripts to automate infrastructure creation using Terraform
- Took the responsibility of an environment champion and resolved any issue in development and production environments
- Actively participated in production deployments during every release

## Global Space Technologies, Mumbai, India

Robotics Intern May 2018 – June 2018

Built an obstacle-avoiding, line-following mobile controllable bot for kids.

## **REWARDS AND RECOGNIZATION**

• Cognizant Cheers Gold award for playing a critical role, showcasing exceptional ownership and leadership qualities, and Silver award for working as one

Cognizant Cheers Bronze award for all the successful deliveries of features crucial for the client

2020